INSTRUCTOR: Hello, everyone
and welcome to the content
video for graphs implementation.
So this content
video covers how do
we go from the logical
structure of a graph
or I understand
how a graph works
or in theory how
it works, how do I
go to now implementing
that or building
an application around that?
So that's what this
content video covers.
So coding a graph.
Again, now that
we're coding it, we
want to look through how do
we keep it computational?
How do we do it fast?
How do we traverse the
graph and calculate things
as efficiently as possible?
The graph is a data
structure itself,
but it's a data structure
that utilizes data structures
and also algorithms, but it
heavily uses these two kind.
One is an adjacency
matrix, you can see where
my mouse is hovering there.
Adjacency matrix, which is just
a 2D list and an adjacency list,
which is a list or a
vector that you can grow,
you can append things to
over and over and over.
So an adjacency matrix
representation, as I mentioned,
it's a 2D array, a 2D list.
You get an index, so it's like
rows and columns that are nodes.
So here it is.
So think of it like
there's nodes, A,B,C,D,
you have those in a column,
you have those in rows,
and whether or not there is
an element at column 2, row 2,
that represents is there an
edge that gets me from that node
to that node?
So 2D list where the data
containing the list is edge
information, and then the row
and columns themselves are
the nodes.
So here's an example.
Here's a graph on the right,
so this is a logical structure.
This is how you think
about it as a human
and view the
relationships and how
to traverse it and
get data out of here
and make decisions
with this data.
But at some point,
you got to code it up.
So that's the 2D list
on the left here.
So all of the 1's in this 2D
array, they represent the nodes.
So think of it like
node 2 here has a loop.
So if you look at the spot
2, 2 in this 2D array,
there's a 1 representing an
edge exists from there to there.
Well, then how come
this isn't a symmetric?
How come all of the
from nodes, the edges
that represent from
and to aren't the same
back and forth because
it's a directed graph.
So if you think of the rows here
as from and then the columns
as to, then you get your
relationship information.
So if a 1 exists,
that's it's from one
column to another column here.
So, for example, let's
take our row here.
So look at this red edge.
So from node 1 to node
2, we have an edge.
So our index starts at 0,
so our row for our node 1
is right here, if you can see
where my mouse is hovering.
And then all of the
edges to other nodes
are represented in
this row right here.
Well, 012, I see this
red 1 right here,
that tells me I've got an edge
from node 1 to node 2 and you
can see it's represented
there like that.
So that would be
edge information.
And here it's just a 1,
but if the edge represents
a mathematical
relationship, then you
just put the number in there.
So adjacency matrix work
really well for any graphs
that store numeric information.
And then here is just
a more complex example
of what we just went over.
All the from and the two are
the rows and the columns.
And then whenever there's
an edge from 1 to another,
it's represented as a 1.
So look at Mary really quick.
Mary has no edges
going to her, let's say
that this represented a
graph point to someone
who's younger than you.
Well, if Mary's
younger than everybody,
Mary doesn't point to anybody,
just everybody points to her.
Well, if you look at the Mary
row or the node at index 0
right here, they're all 0's
in that row because Mary's got
no one to point to.
There's no edges going from
Mary to the other nodes.
Pros and cons.
So this is set up for why
adjacency list exists is
because as you notice,
let me go back a slide,
there's a lot of zeros in there.
There's a lot of data
allocated that's never used.
Well, can we make that
any more efficient?
And by the way, adjacency
matrices and lists
are both used and
I like matrices
because they're really simple
to understand the relationships.
But a big con that you
can't really ignore,
no matter what
you do, the matrix
takes order n squared memory.
An n squared is slower than
we're after, we covered that
through sorting and trees.
But it's a trade
off because they're
simple to understand
but take more space.
So adjacency list.
Adjacency list is,
well, why don't we just
have a list for each node and
then if there's an edge to it,
we just add it to the
list, we append it on.
Then we're really memory
efficient because we're only
adding things to
the adjacency list
when there's actually
an edge to another node.
And that does work well and
it is more memory efficient.
So take a look at these.
So now I've got a list for
each node and I put in the data
where I can get
to from that node.
So take a look at L2 right here.
The John node is 2, I can
get to 0, 1, 4, and 5.
And you can see edges from John
to 0, Mary, Helen 1, Tom 4,
and Paul 5, they're
the edges right there.
So it is more memory
efficient that way.
But you need to account
for different length sizes
now, so if you
write an algorithm
to go through and
find out, well,
who is younger than Mary here?
Your algorithm associated
with that data structure
will be a little
bit more complex
if you use an adjacency list.
So it's a trade off and
in practice both are used.
Directed and undirected graphs.
We covered those in
the overview video,
I just want to add
here though, directed
and undirected also influenced
the data structure itself.
As I mentioned with
matrices, adjacency matrix,
the data is not symmetric in a
matrix if the graph is directed.
So just keep that in mind
that both the data contains
relationship information
whether or not
it's directed or undirected,
that's part of the information.
Examples of undirected graph.
So this would be like a
relationship, so same people,
but the first four are siblings
and the last two are siblings.
So now we've got
relationship information
in the graph which are a sibling
is a yes or no, it doesn't
need a directed relationship.
Older would but are
you a sibling does not.
So here these four
siblings and these two
are not so their
graphs are undirected.
So then you can see here
this changes things.
Now you can see as I
was mentioning earlier,
the adjacency matrix
now is symmetric.
And you can see
where my mouse is at.
All of the axes right
here are 0's, and if you
look at this side right
here, the six 1's right here,
they're symmetric to
these six 1's over here.
Same thing with these
two 1's down here
that represent Tom and Paul are
siblings, they're symmetric.
They're symmetric
because it's undirected.
If there's an edge
from Tom to Paul,
there's an edge from
Paul to Tom every time.
There's no sense of
direction to or from they're
connected period.
So the symmetry in
an adjacency matrix
is expected in undirected
graphs because you
can get to and from any
node, excuse me, if you
can get to a node from a node,
you can get from that node
back to the first node.
And again, that was set
up for how to code a graph
and how to implement it.
And that concludes our content
video on graph implementation.
Thanks for watching.